idexx.com 2016-12-31

# Privacy Policy Statement, United States - IDEXX Laboratories

At IDEXX, we respect the privacy of customers and visitors who use our services and visit our websites, and we strive to keep all personal information secure and confidential. Accordingly, we have adopted the privacy policy described in this statement. (the “Privacy Policy”).

Please note that your information may be processed in countries other than your country of residence and may be transferred to, processed in, or shared within the United States, countries of the European Union, or elsewhere.

IDEXX has self-certified to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield. Please click here to view the IDEXX Privacy Shield Notice.

IDEXX complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from Switzerland. IDEXX has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles and agrees to cooperate with the Swiss federal data protection and information commissioner for disputes received from Switzerland that cannot be directly resolved with IDEXX. To learn more over the Swiss Safe Harbor program, and to view IDEXX’s certification please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor>

##### 1\. Notice

This policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you and how we may use or disclose that information, and describes our efforts to protect it. Please read this policy carefully, and feel free to contact us at the following addresses or numbers if you have any questions regarding its contents or concerns about our use of your information:

  * Email: [chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com)
  * Phone: 1-888-557-6518
  * Fax: 1-888-557-6518 (Attention: Chief Privacy Officer)
  * Mail: IDEXX Laboratories Inc., Attention: Chief Privacy Officer, One IDEXX Drive, Westbrook, Maine 04092, U.S.A.

**_  
_Categories of Information Collected**

We may collect a variety of personal information about you in connection with the offer and sale of our products and services, including

(1) information we receive directly from you via our websites (“Websites”), applications, surveys, or other forms, such as name, address, credit card number, bank account information (if you opt for direct debit), and other contact information;

(2) information about your transactions with us, such as account activity records, including purchases of various products and services;

(3) publicly available information we collect from third parties, including demographic or business information, as well as preferences and opinions regarding various topics; and

(4) information we receive from a consumer reporting agency in connection with your application for credit, which may include account information and/or consumer credit information.

**  
Information Collected via IDEXX Websites**

In connection with your use of our Websites we may ask for and collect a variety of information from and about you. Information may be collected and maintained directly by IDEXX, an IDEXX subsidiary, or by a third party operating under our instructions and subject to this Privacy Policy and/or contractual obligations regarding protection of your information. When you provide personal information to IDEXX through our Websites for purchases, services, requests, and/or any other purpose, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to the collection, use, and transmission of your personal information by IDEXX, as described in this Privacy Policy, for the purposes for which you submitted it.

_Technical Information_ —The Internet Protocol (IP) address that has been assigned to your computer or network by your Internet service provider (ISP) is recognized by our Websites, and a variety of other technical information, such as browser type and connection speed, is also collected.

_Registration Information_ —If you register, sign up for a service, or contact us via email or our Websites, your individually identifiable email address or other personally identifiable information will be collected and stored. This registration information may include your name, address, telephone number, fax number, email address, information about your company or organization, and other information needed for a particular IDEXX program, promotion, or service.

_Credit Card Information_ —If you purchase products or services through IDEXX Online Orders, the credit card information you submit through IDEXX Online Orders, such as name, address, credit card number, and verification number, goes directly to a third-party payment processor. IDEXX does not store or retain credit card information submitted through IDEXX Online Orders.

_About Cookies_ —Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile device by websites that you visit. They help users navigate websites efficiently and enable certain website functionality. Cookies are also used by web developers to measure how you use the website so it can be updated and improved based on your needs. Due to their core role of enhancing and enabling website functionality, you may lose certain functionality if you choose to disable cookies.

**  
Cookies from IDEXX Websites**

_IDEXX Cookies_ —IDEXX cookies are used to remember the selections or preferences that you have made, thereby improving your user experience with the Websites. These cookies allow us to authenticate users of certain IDEXX web applications, to customise a particular user’s experience, to remember if you have accepted our use of cookies on your device, and to perform other personalization functions. We may also use these cookies to learn more about how users navigate through our sites. If you disable the IDEXX cookies, you may still use the Websites but may not have access to or use of certain services. To opt out of being tracked by IDEXX cookies across all Websites, see **How to disable or delete cookies** , below.

_Google Analytics Cookies_ —Google Analytics cookies (for example, utma, utmb, utmc, utmz, utmv) collect aggregated information about how visitors use our Website; for instance, how many unique visitors we have to our sites, what pages on our Website you visit, how long you are on our Websites, and how you got here, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. The data is then aggregated to help us understand how visitors are using our site so that we can create a better experience for you.

Our U.S. Website also uses the following Google Analytics Advertising Features: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, and integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. We use these Google Analytics Advertising Features and cookies on our U.S. Website to enable us to reach out to you with information relevant to your interests, using approaches such as targeted online direct and display advertising, as well placement of relevant ads in search engines you use.

Information collected from Google Analytics and Google Analytics Advertising Features cookies may be transmitted to and stored by Google and is subject to [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/privacy.html). To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics and Google Analytics Advertising Features across all of our Websites, see **How to disable or delete cookies** , below.

_How to disable or delete cookies_ —Information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at [aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/). Please note that by deleting cookies or disabling future cookies you may be prevented from utilizing certain website functionality. If you want to restrict or block the cookies placed on your computer or device, you'll need to refer to your website browser settings to change settings or block cookies. You may also opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting Google's [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) or the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Google Analytics is a trademark of Google Inc.

**Use of Information**

IDEXX uses your personal information solely:

  * to respond to your request for products, services, or information;
  * to fulfill our obligations to you under orders or contracts;
  * to arrange for and process payments owed by you in connection with orders or contracts;
  * or for internal purposes, including without limitation, marketing, promotions, customer support, Website administration, and feedback purposes.

If at any time you supply a mailing address, telephone or fax number, or email address to us, you may receive, if permitted under applicable law, periodic mailings, telephone calls, faxes, or emails, whichever the case may be, with information on new IDEXX products and services or upcoming events. We may also aggregate statistics that we gather about customers, sales, or Website traffic and provide this information to third parties on a non-personally identifiable (aggregated) basis.

**  
Disclosure of Information**

Information may be exchanged among IDEXX, its subsidiaries, and service providers as needed for business purposes, such as account administration, customer service, transaction processing, consumer reporting, processing and delivery of account statements, research and analysis, and delivery of products and services.

IDEXX will use contractual or other measures to require service providers to maintain a level of privacy protection comparable to our own practices.

IDEXX may also share information with joint marketing partners to present certain offers to you, but these parties will only be able to access and use your personal information for this limited purpose. In addition, if you opt for direct debit as a payment method, we will share certain personal information with your financial institution in order to arrange for payment. IDEXX does not sell email addresses, telephone or fax numbers, or other personally identifiable information to other companies. We may disclose information to fulfill certain legal and regulatory requirements if we believe that such disclosure is legally required or necessary to protect our legal rights or the rights of others, or to prevent harm, or in accordance with your instructions.

For government information requests, we comply with the laws applicable to us and other entities that process our data, and we provide details only as legally required. For content requests from law enforcement agencies outside the U.S., with the exception of emergency circumstances (defined in the Electronic Communications Privacy Act 1986, as amended), IDEXX will only provide content in response to a search warrant issued pursuant to the Mutual Legal Assistance Treaty process or through other cooperative efforts with the United States Department of Justice.

Our policy is to notify people who use our Websites and services of requests for their information prior to our disclosure of it, unless we are prohibited by law from doing so or in exceptional circumstances such as emergencies. We will provide delayed notice upon expiration of a specific nondisclosure period in a court order and where we have a good faith belief that exceptional circumstances no longer exist and we are not otherwise prohibited by law from doing so. Law enforcement officials who believe that notification would jeopardize an investigation should obtain an appropriate court order or other appropriate process establishing that notice is prohibited. If our investigation into your data request indicates to us that there is an ongoing violation of our terms of use, we will take action to prevent further abuse, including actions that may notify the user that we are aware of their misconduct.

#####  2\. Choice Regarding Consent

If you object to the use by IDEXX, its subsidiaries, or service providers of your personal information for the purposes described above, or if you do not wish to receive mail, email, telephone calls, or faxes about IDEXX products or services, you may request IDEXX to stop such use, mailings, or telephone calls by notifying the Chief Privacy Officer at [chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com) or at an address or telephone or fax number specified above. Emails sent on our behalf include instructions for unsubscribing from our email distribution lists.

#####  3\. Access and Updates

At any time after you have submitted personally identifiable information to us, you may contact us at [chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com](mailto:chiefprivacyofficer@idexx.com) or at an address or telephone or fax number specified above to request access to information we have collected regarding you or your business or to notify us of changes to such information. If you request any such changes, we will contact you by email or fax to confirm those changes. Once confirmed, any new item or information will replace the corresponding information previously provided.

#####  4\. Security

We use commercially reasonable physical, procedural, and technical safeguards to deter unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure of individually identifiable information. We instruct our employees that information must be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and any misuse by employees is subject to disciplinary action.

If you provide any information to parties who operate websites that are linked to or from our site, different rules may apply to their collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review these sites’ policies before revealing any sensitive or personal information.

Regardless of the precautions taken by you or us, “perfect security” does not exist. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you transmit sensitive information at your own risk.

#####  5\. Enforcement

We have implemented a self-assessment process to verify adherence to the terms of this policy. If you have any complaints regarding our use and/or disclosure of your personal information, please contact our Chief Privacy Officer through the contact information provided above. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes by reference to the principles contained in this policy.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

It may be necessary from time to time for us to modify this policy to reflect changes in the way we collect and use information or changes in privacy-related laws, regulations, and industry standards. We will provide reasonable notice of material changes to this policy, including via links posted on IDEXX Websites. Visitors should view this page from time to time to review the then-current policy.

**Website**

This site is administered and maintained by IDEXX Laboratories, Inc., of Westbrook, Maine, U.S.A. Use of this site is governed by the [Terms of Use](https://www.idexx.com/corporate/common/terms-of-use.html) and indicates acceptance of such terms. 

_  _Last updated: September 26, 2016_ _
